好痛！好痛！
It hurts! It hurts!
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
- 好痛! - 你在哪儿？
- It hurts! - Where are you?
好痛! 好痛！
It hurts! It hurts!
滚出来！
Get out!
- 出来，该死的! - 好痛! 好痛！
- Get out, damn it! - It hurts! It hurts!
在哪儿? 你把它藏哪儿了？
Where is it? Where did you hide it?
- 什么? - 长矛
- What? - Lance.
他们用来杀我的那个
The one with which they killed me.
督察
Inspector.
督察我可以走了吗？
Inspector, can I go?
- 谁值班? - 斯维塔，米利萨夫和我
- Who was on duty? - Sveta, Milisav, and I.
马上把他们带过来
Bring them here, now.
他们已经走了...下班了，我也该下班了
Well, they're gone... Their shift is over, and so is mine.
叫醒他们，带来见我
Wake them up and bring them.
- 我会在酒吧等你们 - 好的
- I'll be in the Little Barrel. - Okay.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第七集
BLACK SUN Episode 7
将军...你为什么要突然离开？
General... Why are you leaving so sudden?
没人听说你要走
Nobody knows you are going away.
大家都很担心，他们想见你
People are worried. They would like to see you.
也许你可以为我组织一场
Maybe you want to organise a ceremonial parade for me,
与我们伟大的胜利相称阅兵仪式
as would be fitting to our great triumph?
我从来不太重视遗物
I never gave too much importance to the relics.
但是作为一名士兵，我非常清楚
But as a soldier, I know very well
在正确的人手里任何一只长矛都是朗基努斯之矛
that in the right hands, every lance is the lance of Longinus...
我也知道那个符号的含义
I also know the meaning of a symbol.
但我更清楚战争使命的意义
But I know even better what a war mission means.
如果我们连保护我们国家的象征
If we were unable to fulfil such a simple mission,
这样一个简单的任务都不能完成
to save the symbol of our state,
那么拿什么来拯救
then what can the empire,
被亵渎者征服的帝国
conquered by the Christ's profanes, count on,
如果它指望我们来拯救它呢？
if it counted on us to save it?
如果有比我地位更高的人
If there was someone of a higher rank than me
我可以把我的职责交给他
to whom I could hand over my duties,
作为一个可敬的战士，毫无疑问
as an honourable soldier, I would, without any doubt,
我愿把我的生命交给他
offer him my life.
因为我没有完成任务
Because I failed to fulfil my assignment.
孩子
Son...
塞尔维亚的军队就交给你了
our men in Serbia, I leave them to you
我祈祷... 你会成为
and I pray... that you will become
一个好的指挥官
a good commander.
萨沙，我们走
Sasha, let's go.
甜点来了，还有你的白兰地，塔尼
Guys, here's something sweet, and a brandy for you, Tane.
不要白兰地，我要他喝的那个
Take that away. Give me what he's drinking
- 格瓦斯? - 是的
- A kvass? - Yes.
时代变了
Times, they're a changin'...
你为什么这么严肃？
Why are you so grim?
你的工作做得很好
You did your job well.
- 我想知道谁没做好 - 我们会查到的
- I want to know who didn't. - We'll get to that.
- 吃吧 - 我不饿
- C'mon, eat. - I'm not hungry.
局长先生，好久不见，我给你做了个馅饼
Mr. Commissioner! Long time! I have a pie for you.
去他妈的馅饼！
Fuck off with the pie!
- 塔纳西耶维奇在哪儿? - 我在这儿！
- Where is Tanasiyevich? - Here I am!
你去哪儿了？
Where've you been?
你已经好几天没来上班了，你睡在哪条沟里
You haven't come to work for days. In what ditch were you sleeping
在朱基奇给我施压的时候? 你有什么要告诉我的吗？
while Djolovich was busting my ass? Do you have anything to tell me?
哦，什么也别说，求你了! 你给他打电话了吗？
Oh, don't say anything, please! Did you call him?
- 谁? - 朱基奇！
- Whom? - Djolovich!
你听说凶手在监狱里自杀了吗？
And did you hear the murderer committed a suicide in the prison?
是的，他意识到自己会被绞死，所以提前结束了自己的痛苦
Yes. He realised he'd be hanged, so he put himself out of misery.
- 他应该被审判的 - 你说什么？
- He should have been tried. - I beg your pardon?
然后再处以绞刑，不管是哪个警察帮了他
And then hanged. Whichever of our cops helped him,
都是犯罪，一定会受到惩罚
they committed a crime, and it won't go unpunished.
一定！
It will!
一个杀人犯被杀了，被处决了，怎么说都行
A murderer got murdered, executed, how ever you want to put it.
重要的是他不会再杀人了
It's important that he won't kill anymore.
你在怀疑我的人？
You doubt my cops?
你认为有人给了他一把剃刀? 也许是我？
You think someone gave him a razor? Maybe it was me?
他自己动的手
He cut his own throat.
我不管，他死了，一切都结束了！
I don't care! He's dead and it's over!
- 我不同意 - 谁问你了！
- I can't agree with that. - Who asked you!
- 滚开! - 嘿，日沃因！
- Fuck off! - Hey, Zhivoyin!
坐下，坐下，喝一杯
Sit down, sit down. Have a drink.
我想我们得想办法解决这个问题
I think we'll have to sort this out somehow.
的确，不管是谁给的剃刀
It's true it doesn't matter who passed the razor,
而是谁下的命令，这更重要
but it matters who ordered it.
阿夫拉姆 · 奈斯托维奇并不是单独行动的
Avram Nestorovich didn't work alone.
他开了个头，后面还有其他人会完成
He started the job, and somebody else will finish it.
你会明白的
You'll see.
- 完成什么? - 我不知道
- Finish what? - I don't know.
给我一杯烈酒！
Give us a shot!
该死的，我不知道该怎么想
God damn it, I don't know what to think.
但是我觉得很快就会有人再次受到伤害
But I feel that someone will get hurt again, and very soon.
我会盯着这个叫沃因·朱基奇的家伙
I would keep an eye on this Voyin Djukich guy.
我为什么要监视他? 他是国家检察官
Why should I keep an eye on him? He is a state prosecutor.
有军队在保护他
The army is guarding him.
我告诉过你，随你的便
I told you. Do as you wish.
塔尼，我知道你会如愿以偿的
Tane, I know you will do as you intended to,
不过不要小题大做
but don't make a fuss.
到处调查，提问…
Investigate, question...
别把我的人扯进来！
but leave my gendarmes out of this!
告诉我，你怎么能忍受这一切？
Tell me, how can you put up with all this?
你没看见他在限制我们行动吗？
Can't you see that he's tying our hands all the way?
那我们现在该怎么办？
And what are we supposed to do now?
总是做他们告诉你的相反的事情，就不会有问题
Always do the opposite of what they told you, and you won't fuck up.
放松，吃饭吧
Take it easy and be careful. Now, eat.
我告诉过你我不饿
I told you I am not hungry.
- 再见，普尔莎 - 再见
- Hi Prsha. - Hello, Pletikosa.
我的玛塔 · 哈莉来了！
Here comes my Mata Hari!
- 我们有大麻烦了 - 真的吗？
- We have a big problem. - Really?
一些罪证材料..
A certain incriminating material...
之前在我手上
was at our fingertips.
但是由于一些原因，现在已经消失了
But due to unfortunate coincidence it is now gone.
你是说这个材料，对吗？
You mean this material, right?
听着
Listen, man.
如果有人想耍小聪明，并且耍明白了
When someone tries to be smart and gets lucky,
我通常会视而不见
I usually turn a blind eye,
但如果没耍明白，真的应该直接被枪毙
but when they fuck up, they really ought be shot.
如果你认为这样就能解决问题..
If you think you'll solve the case that way...
不，你会解决的
No, you will solve it.
只有等你在我办公室看到他的时候
And you'd inform me that the bastard is in Belgrade
你才会告诉我那个混蛋在贝尔格莱德，是吗？
only when you see him in my office, eh?
哪个混蛋? 混蛋太多了
Which bastard? There are so many of them.
戈伊科·塔明吉奇
Goyko Tamindgich,
菲利克斯，伊斯梅特，那个有着上千张脸的人..
Felix, Ismet, the man with a thousand faces...
我们两个都在他的暗杀名单上？
who has both of us on his hit list?
我们不确定戈伊科是否在贝尔格莱德
We're not sure that Golubich is in Belgrade.
你不确定，是吗？
You're not sure. Is that so?
不完全确定
Not completely sure.
你知道我们现在是在什么鬼地方吗？
Do you understand the kind of shithole we're in?
人们的脑袋像奥斯曼帝国时代一样在地上滚来滚去
Heads are rolling around like we're in Ottoman times.
马其顿发生火灾，帕夫里奇来倒汽油！
Macedonia is on fire, Pavelich pours gasoline!
那个沃兰赫尔在我们的大街上阅兵，好像这里是一个俄罗斯的省！
That Vrangel parades his army as if this is a Russian province!
所有人都在做鸦片生意！
His people want opium, our people want opium!
而你们这些人，竟然跟我说"不完全确定”？
And you people, "are not completely sure".
我明白..
I understand...
你明白个屁，坐下
You understand shit. Sit down.
我来告诉你该怎么做
I'll tell you what you're going to do.
首先，你要联系阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇
First, you'll contact Alimpiye Mirich.
旅途愉快吗，阿尔索夫太太？
Did you have a pleasant trip, Mrs. Hadgy-Arsov?
那是我哥哥的姓
That's my brother's surname.
我随我丈夫的姓
I took my husband's.
真的? 你这么年轻就结婚了？
Really? You got married young?
我年纪轻轻就守寡了
I also got widowed young.
多亏了你们塞尔维亚人和你们的解放者国王
Thanks to you Serbs, and your King the Liberator.
我们的国王是一个多才多艺的人，他很喜欢，这么说吧..
Our king is a versatile person. He likes to, let's say...
解放女性
Liberate the female population.
他是一个有点生活品味的人
He's a bit of a bon vivant.
但对你来说，这就是贵族
But that's royalty for you.
我们的亚历山大大帝不是一个好色之徒，也不是一个冒险家
Our Alexander the Great was not a womanizer and an adventurer.
他是个真正的国王
He was a real king.
- 那是因为他是同性恋 - 什么？
- That's because he was a gay. - What?
告诉我，马其顿不是希腊北部的一个省吗？
And tell me, isn't Macedonia a province in northern Greece?
- 不！不是! - 不是？
- No, it's not! - It's not?
那我一定是弄错了，我的错
I must have made a mistake. My bad.
基拉，我的人会告诉你确切的时间
Kyro, my man will inform you about the exact time
什么时候对监狱发动攻击
when to commence an attack on the prison.
请耐心点
Please, be patient.
我们有的是耐心
Don't you worry about us.
已经等了十六年了
We've been waiting for sixteen years.
真的吗? 为什么是十六年？
Really? Why sixteen?
因为十六年前你们占领了我们的国家
Cause that's when you occupied us.
我必须承认
I must admit,
贝尔格莱德已经有一段时间没有出现这么稀有的野兽了
it's been some time since we had such a rare beast here in Belgrade.
对我们来说，减少不必要的反抗是很重要的
It's important for us that we don't face too much resistance.
我们会试图在贝尔格莱德周围分散这支部队
We will try to spread that force thin around Belgrade.
但我必须指出一点: 你看...
But I have to point something out: You see...
这里不是保加利亚边境的边远哨所
this is not a remote outpost on Bulgarian border,
也不是一条山路，只有一个像你这样的恶棍
nor a mountain road where one lousy bandit, such as yourself,
和一群白痴在一起，试图伏击喝醉的宪兵
with a group of idiots, tries to ambush drunken gendarmes,
也不是女强盗可以在光天化日之下随便杀死警察局长的村庄
or a village where a girl-bandit can cut down the police chief
你的故事我都知道
in a broad daylight. I know all about that.
这是一个大城市，这是贝尔格莱德
This is a big city. This is Belgrade.
在我们的小演出之后，它会演变成一场大型的街头战争
And after our little gig, it'll explode into one big street war.
它会吞噬你我
It will engulf you, me,
还有我的生意
and my business.
对我来说，这是一个巨大的风险
And for me that's one hell of a risk.
所以你有三分钟时间救走你的人
So, you'll have three minutes to free your guy.
一秒也不能多
And not a second more.
如果你失败了
If you fail,
如果你没死在宪兵手上
and if the gendarmes somehow don't kill you,
那就是死在我手上
I will personally finish you off.
听着，日沃因，我知道你是个正直的警察
Listen, Zhivoyin. I know you're a real officer,
你永远不会帮助这样一个人渣
and that you'd never help such a scum.
我不会，永远不会
I wouldn't. Never.
- 我以我孩子起誓 - 我知道所以我才问你
- I swear on my children. - I know. That's why I'm asking you.
- 是他们俩谁干的？ - 都有可能，我不知道
- Which of the two is it? - Could be either. I don't know.
是的，但是哪一个呢？
Yes, but which one?
说实话，他们都是混蛋
To be honest, they're both jerks.
我一点也不相信他们
I don't trust them one bit.
这种事一个人做不了，得有人帮帮他
He couldn't do it by himself. Somebody had to help him out.
我不知道，督察，他们都是好人
I don't know, inspector. They're good people.
我不相信他们中的任何一个能做出这样的事
I don't believe either of them could do such a thing.
如果不是日沃因
Look, if it's not Zhivoyin,
也不是斯维塔，那么…
and it's not Sveta, then...
米利萨夫，出去
Milisav, get out.
我不是告诉过你不要碰我的人吗？
Haven't I told you to leave my gendarmes alone?
你说过
You have.
我刚和米利萨夫谈过，我想这事到底是不是他做的
I just talked to Milisav and I think it's him or if not him...
你在哪上的学? ！
Which school did you go to?!
你知道米利萨夫在战斗中救了一个排的士兵吗？
Did you know that Milisav saved a platoon of soldiers in the battle?
- 你在指控我最好的下属? - 局长…
- You're accusing my best man? - Mr. Commissioner...
你不仅不会指控他，而且我还要提拔他！
Not only you won't accuse him, but I'm going to promote him!
你这个傻瓜！
You fool!
- 米利萨夫 - 什么事，局长？
- Milisav! - Yes, Mr. Commissioner?
从现在开始你当我的司机，你升职了
You're driving me from now on. You're being promoted.
- 没问题吧? - 谢谢
- Right? - Thank you.
立即生效! 我们走！
Effective immediately! Let's go!
很好，真的很好
Great. Really great.
- 我没拿到那些底片 - 真的吗? 你可以走了
- I didn't get those negatives. - Oh, really? You can go.
- 你不想知道在谁手上? - 我知道的时候你就给我扯淡
- You don't want to know who has them? - When I did, you fed me bullshit.
- 现在没人在乎了 - 我问你
- Now, nobody cares. - Let me ask you something.
什么? 你知道你把我拉进了多深的坑吗? 脖子那么深，高兴了吧？
What? How deep is the hole you put me in? It's neck-deep. Happy?
通知你一下，进门密码"Rajatz"已经失效了
Just so you know, the code Rajatz isn't valid any more.
我们的头号嫌疑犯昨晚自杀了
Our prime suspect committed suicide last night.
不是我们的，是你的
Not our. Your.
没有你的部门这个案子就破不了
This case can't be solved without your department.
你得帮我们找到那个和尚，他是一切的关键
You have to help us find the Monk. He is the key for everything.
忘了那个名字吧，塔尼
Forget that name, Tane.
这是我最后的友好建议，明白吗？
That's my last friendly advice. Understand?
当国家检察官丢了脑袋
When the state prosecutor loses his head,
和尚的名字还是不能提吗？
will the name of the Monk still be forbidden?
或者他是为了我而死，而不是为了你？
Or would he be dead for me, and not for you?
记住我说的，忘了朱基奇
Remember what I said. And forget about Djukich.
你终于出现了
You showed up finally.
你什么时候才能意识到商业不是游戏？
When will you realise that business is not a game?
你在想什么呢? 想来就来，想走就走？
What do you think? One day you're in, the next day not.
当他们把你赶出股东会时，不要感到惊讶
Don't be surprised when they won't let you make the decisions.
如果你累了，我们以后再谈
If you are tired, we'll talk later.
把银行章程给我
Bring me the bank's charter.
为什么？
Why?
这样我才能开始做决定
So I can start making the decisions.
没错
That's right.
现在你表现得像个真正的女商人
Now you are acting as a real businesswoman.
我马上把文件拿给你
I'll bring you the documents. Right away.
你找到维也纳联合创始人的资料了吗？
Did you find anything about the co-founders from Vienna?
没有
No.
- 抱歉，我迟到了 - 你总是这样
- Sorry I'm late. - As you usually are.
亲爱的公爵，我是不是听出了你的不满？
Am I sensing dissatisfaction in your voice, dear duke?
我知道你不熟悉贵族头衔
I know you're not familiar with noble titles,
但我真的不敢相信
but to be unable to distinguish a count from a duke,
你竟然分不清伯爵和公爵
I just can't believe.
这是礼貌的说法
It's a matter of manners.
如果任何一个混蛋可以被称为”先生”
If any bastard can be called "sir"
那为什么不把一个伯爵提升为公爵呢？
then why not promote one count into a duke?
- 只是出于礼貌 - 没关系
- Just for the sake of courtesy. - It's alright.
我没有责备你迟到，我只是在开玩笑
I'm not reproaching you for being late. I was just joking.
那太好了，亲爱的公爵，抱歉，伯爵
Even better, dear duke. Sorry, earl.
你有没有听说最近有些女孩子们消失得无影无踪？
Did you hear that girls are disappearing without a trace?
还有成吨的马其顿鸦片也是一样
And tonnes of Macedonian poppy.
作为交换，钱会到位的
And in exchange, the money arrives.
你能怎么办? 有的人躺在俄罗斯女孩身上抽鸦片
What can you do? Someone shags Russian girls and smokes opium,
而有的人却要工作，但这就是你的生活
while someone has to work. But that's life for you.
但是生意就是生意，不是吗？
But business is business, isn't it?
当然
It sure is.
- 我在认真听 - 那你最好认真读读这个
- I am listening very carefully. - Then you better read carefully.
这是一份你期待已久的
This is the contract worth one million
价值一百万的合同
that you've been waiting for so long.
当你注册你的特权公司时立即生效
It comes into effect when you register your privileged company.
- 我是怎么走到这一步的? - 这是你应得的
- How did I deserve this? - You're yet do deserve it.
你认识沃因 · 朱基奇先生吗？
Do you know Mr. Voyin Djukich?
你前男友来了
Your ex-boyfriend is here.
检察官先生，他又变得冷酷无情了
Mr. Prosecutor. He's grim again.
- 谢谢你能来 - 不客气
- Thanks for coming. - Of course.
- 要喝点什么吗? - 不用了
- Would you like something to drink? - No, no.
你怎么能就这样消失了呢？
How could you disappear like that?
我不知道你在哪里，也不知道发生了什么..
I didn't know where you were, or what had happened...
是你说我们要暂停一下
You wanted us to take a break.
我从没这么说过，这不公平
I never said that! It's not fair.
我们能单独谈谈吗？
Can we please have some privacy?
我不介意，请继续
I don't mind, please go on.
科萨，穿好衣服，让大人们说话
Kosa, get dressed and let the grown-ups talk.
他才不想说话呢
He doesn't care about the talk.
看到他看我们的眼神了吗？
See how is he looking at us?
我们两个都要吗？
Would you like to have us both?
科萨，你一点都不好笑了
Kosa, you're not funny anymore.
- 收拾东西走人 - 去哪儿？
- Pack up your things and leave. - Go where?
你出去之后慢慢想
You'll think of something when you get out of here.
- 请坐 - 你应该知道..
- Have a seat, please. - You should know...
我拿走了项链
that I took Violet's necklace from here.
我知道，没关系
I know. It's okay.
沃兰赫尔将军亲自要我还给他
General Vrangel personally asked me to return it to him.
沃兰赫尔？
Vrangel?
天啊，她到底惹了什么麻烦？
Jesus, what has she gotten into?
我不知道，但是她把我也拖下水了，所以把它还回去了
I don't know, but she got me too. I returned it.
但是他后来打电话给我，听起来很生气
But he called me later and sounded really aggravated.
他说有东西不见了
He said something was missing.
你有没有拿走或者碰过什么东西？
Did you take or touch anything?
我? 是你把那个倒霉项链带到我家来
Me? You brought that stupid thing into my house.
- 我从没碰过 - 好的
- I never touched it. - Right.
好吧，没关系
Okay. It doesn't matter.
你知道最重要的是什么吗？
You know what matters?
你打电话给我的时候我意识到我有多想你
I realized how much I missed you when you called me.
我还以为你也想我呢
I thought you missed me too.
我打电话给你是为了银行的事
I called you about the bank.
我想我们有好消息了
I think we have good news.
好吧，我明白了
Okay. I understand.
- 沃因... - 没事
- Voyin... - All right.
现在我至少知道该期待什么了
Now I at least know what to expect.
- 我把钥匙还给你 - 别这样
- I'm returning you your keys. - Voyin, really.
银行怎么办？
What about the bank?
帕帕哈吉召集了一次会议，他说有了一个解决方案
Papahagi called a meeting. He said a solution came up.
孩子，手别乱动
Boy, easy with the hands.
你老板呢？
Where's your boss?
他不在，但他向你问好
He's away, but he sends his regards.
你好啊，赫泽戈瓦茨？
How's it going, Hertzegovatz?
我亲爱的赫泽戈瓦茨！
My dear Hertzegovatz!
时代真的在变，室友，当你来救我的时候
Times really are changing, roomie, when you have to come to my rescue.
看起来他们真的是..
Looks like they really are...
你陷害我，然后又救了我，对吗？
You set me up, you save me, is that right?
你知道事情比看起来要复杂得多
You know that things are more complicated than they look.
是啊... 你说说…
Yeah... You tell me...
我从没来过这里
I was never here,
你也应该尽快消失
and you should disappear as soon as possible.
你把照片给我，就当我从来没出现过
You give me the pictures and it'll be as if I never existed.
什么照片? 没有照片
What pictures? There are no pictures.
是这样吗？
Is that so?
- 但是有子弹啊 - 你都有了
- But there are bullets. - You got it all.
他们想杀了你
They tried to kill you.
走吧，如果你问我的话
You were faster, and if you ask me,
你意识到这有多危险，就回到了俄罗斯
you realised how dangerous it was and returned to Russia.
亲爱的室友，当我看到他们想赶我走
My dear roomie, when I see how they're trying to get rid of me,
我可以在广场中央搭一个帐篷
I can set up a tent in the middle of the main square.
他们失手过一次
They messed it up once,
不会再失手了
they'll hardly mess it up again.
谢谢，兄弟
Thanks, mate.
而这个..
And this...
你不会承认我对那位女士的判断是对的吧？
You won't admit that I was right about the lady?
正如我所说，糟糕的时代已经到来
As I said, bad times have arrived.
请给我面包
Bread, please.
你吃太多面包了，这就是你发胖的原因
You eat too much bread. That's why you got fat.
谁在乎呢，反正我是一个人
Who cares, I'm alone anyway.
- 你在说什么? - 怎么了？
- What are you talking about? - What am I talking about?
- 我老了，没人要我 - 但你有个女儿！
- I'm old, nobody wants me. - But you have a daughter!
真希望我有个女儿... 来减轻我的负担
Wish I had a daughter... To lift some burden off my back.
你会的，现在生孩子还不晚
You will. It's not late for you to give birth.
- 如果我有个儿子呢? - 怎么样？
- And what if I have a boy? - Well?
我不是傻瓜，那意味着他三十岁之前所有的开销都要我承担
I'm not a fool. That means expenses until he's thirty.
玛拉！
Mara!
- 安静，他是警察 - 我知道
- Be quiet, he's a cop. - I know.
玛拉！
Mara!
别再找她了，玛拉不在这里
Stop looking for her. Mara is not here.
走开
Go away.
- 你能告诉我她在哪儿吗? - 我就是你的玛拉
- Can you tell me where she is? - I'll be your Mara.
谢谢，但我需要她，我在帮她的忙
Thank you, but I need her. I'm helping her with something.
- 你在帮她? - 是的
- You're helping her? - Yes.
我们的老板把她带走了
Our boss took her away.
是那个叫斯塔夫拉的家伙，对吧？
It's that Stavra guy, right?
谢谢你
Thank you.
当斯塔夫拉听到这个消息，他会揍死你，你这个傻瓜！
When Stavra hears about this, he'll kick your ass, you fool!
去死吧
Go to hell.
将军，国家检察官来了
General, State Prosecutor is here.
让他进来
He may come in.
朱基奇，你到底去哪儿了？
Djukich, where the hell have you been?
下午好，将军
Good afternoon, general.
要不要来杯白兰地？
Would you like a cognac?
不用了，谢谢，我头疼
No, thank you. I have a headache.
真聪明，我向上帝发誓，时代太糟糕了
Clever. The times are awful, I swear to God.
审判进行得怎么样了？
How is that trial going on?
帕维里奇律师妨碍了审判，我不知道他下一步会怎么做
Pavelich obstructed the trial. I don't know his next step,
或者他是否会在下次听证会上出现
or if he'll show up at the next hearing.
我去处理帕维里奇
Pavelich is my concern.
你的工作就是加快进程，解决所有问题
Your job is to speed up the process and solve everything.
- 清楚了吗? - 是的，当然
- Is that clear? - Yes. Of course.
- 沃兰赫尔想要什么? - 这是个问题
- What did Vrangel want? - That's a problem.
那个将军想要的东西..
That thing that general wants...
我解决不了
It appears that I cannot solve it.
那就不用解决了
Then don't.
去他妈的俄罗斯人
Fuck the Russians.
我们正在改变对他们的政策
We're changing our policy about them.
- 晚上好，费奥多先生 - 抬杆子
- Good evening, Mr. Fyodor. - Lift it up.
再见，费奥多先生
Goodbye, Mr. Fyodor.
一切都还好吧，舍夫凯特少爷？
Is everything alright, Master Shevket?
一切顺利
As far as I am concerned, everything is fine.
给他
Give it to him.
一路顺风
Bon voyage.
- 他们人呢? - 我不知道
- Where are they? - I don't know.
快，开门！
Quick! Open it!
有埋伏! 我们走！
It's is an ambush! Let's go!
- 特纳瓦茨... - 嗯？
- Trnavatz... - Eh?
那辆卡车归你了
You just got yourself a new truck.
非常感谢，兄弟
Thanks a lot, bro.
你没什么要跟我说的吗？
You have nothing to say to me?
我没想到会在这里见到你
I didn't expect to meet you here.
这就是你要说的？
And that's the greatest problem?
相信我，我只是个小角色
Trust me, nothing depends on me.
上面命令，要把宪兵转移到另一个任务
The order came to move gendarmes to another assignment.
就这？
And that's it?
看看是否能在更高的级别解决这个问题
Let's see if it can be solved on a higher level.
你我的上级，让他们解决这个问题
Your general to my general. Let them solve the issue.
你拿了钱，别人帮你解决问题
You get the money, while others solve your problems.
我的将军现在不在了，我要接替他的位置
My general is now gone and I am replacing him.
而且，我和你们的将军没有交易
And, I don't have a deal with your general.
我和你倒是有个交易
I have a deal with you.
相信我，我会一如既往地竭尽全力
Believe me I'll do everything in my power, as always.
你有三天时间告诉我和尚是什么人，他藏在哪里
You have three days to tell me who is Monk and where's he hiding.
我认为我们不仅要关注和尚
I don't think that Monk is our only concern.
接着说…
Go on...
这事不会就此结束
This will not end here.
他们在为你准备一个恶心的惊喜
They're preparing a nasty surprise for you.
- 这是什么鬼东西? - 喝了它，有益健康
- What in the hell is this? - Drink it up. It's healthy.
你戒酒后看起来好多了
You look much better since you quit drinking.
这个位子有人坐吗？
Is this seat taken?
没有，请坐
No, have a seat, please.
你在等人吗？
Are you expecting someone?
等除了你之外的人
Anyone but you.
- 你来这里干什么? - 我来见我的救世主
- Why did you come? - I came to see my saviour.
- 这是唯一的原因吗? - 这个原因还不够好吗？
- Is that the only reason? - Isn't that good enough?
我想我很了解你，我知道这不是真的
I think I know you well enough to know that it's not true.
我很抱歉你对我有这样的看法
I'm sorry you have such an opinion about me.
然而你是对的
And even more because you're right.
我来是想问你..
I came to ask you...
看看谁来了! 我的弟媳妇! 欢迎！
Look who's here! My sister-in-law! Welcome!
别这样，斯米利亚... ... 别再说什么姻亲的废话了
Come on, Smilya... Enough with that in-law crap, please.
- 你好吗? 普尔莎先生呢? - 他总是到处跑
- How are you? And Mr. Prsho? - Well, he's always running around.
请坐，你想吃点什么吗？
Have a seat. Would you like something to eat?
- 不不... - 我这有很棒的肉冻
- No, no... - I have great aspic.
谢谢...一杯酒就好了
Thanks... Just a glass of wine.
别管什么肉冻了，给她拿点喝的
Forget the aspic. Bring her something to drink.
我找到了关于项链的线索
I found something about the necklace.
- 真的? - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
维奥莱塔的项链属于沃兰赫尔将军
Violet's necklace belonged to General Vrangel.
沃因把它还了回去
Voyin returned it.
所以他现在应该安全了
So, he should be safe now.
我不太确定
I'm not so sure.
- 为什么? - 我不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
不管怎样，至少我们知道俄罗斯人还没有砍掉他们的脑袋
Anyway, we know now that Russians are not chopping the heads off.
给你，弟媳妇，我不会打扰你了，你可以..
There you go, sis-in-law. I won't bother you, you can...
- 那好 - 干杯
- All right then. - Cheers.
你想问我什么？
And what was it you wanted to ask me?
我还需要你帮个忙
I need another favour.
这是我银行的章程
This is the charter of my bank.
这里有所有的股东姓名和个人文件
Here you have all the names and personal documents.
除了我父亲拥有40%股份之外
Besides my father, who owns 40%,
还有一些当地的人渣，他们持有另外40% 的股份
and some local scum, who holds another 40%,
但持有20%股份的人来自维也纳
but 20% belong to some people from Vienna.
我从没见过他们，没人知道他们的事
I never saw them. Nobody knows anything about them.
难以置信，但却是事实，就连帕帕哈吉也不知道
It's incredible, but true. Not even Papahagi
你不知道谁是你父亲的合伙人？
You don't know who are the partners of your father?
我连我父亲都不认识，更别说他的合伙人了
Inspector, I didn't even know my father, let alone his partners.
帮我找出一些关于他们的事情
Help me to find out something about them.
为什么朱基奇先生没有帮你解决这个问题？
Why didn't Mr. Djukich solve it for you?
他什么也找不到
He couldn't find anything.
那你就来找我这个醉醺醺的警察？
And now all you have left is one drunken cop?
- 塔尼 - 看看谁来了
- Tane. - Look at them.
- 晚上好 - 晚上好，博雅纳
- Good evening. - Good evening, Boyana.
- 晚上好 - 请坐
- Good evening. - Have a seat.
近来可好？
How are you?
听着孩子，如果你想让一个女孩爱上你
Listen, kid. If you want a girl to fall in love with you,
永远不要带她去小酒桶酒吧
never bring her to Little Barrel.
你根本不知道! 这地方很棒
You don't have a clue! This is the ideal place.
他不想让那个女孩爱上他
He doesn't want the girl to fall in love with him.
哦，真的吗? 那他想要什么？
Oh, really? What does he want?
真的吗？
Really?
上帝与我们同在
在这儿，我找到了！
It's here! I found it!
我以为我永远失去它了
I thought I lost it forever.
你把它弄丢了
You lost it.
不，不！
No, no!
遗物找到了，我们的家园得救了！
The relic is saved, and our homeland is saved!
在这里！
Here it is!
什么也救不了! 一切都没了！
Nothing can be saved! Everything is lost!
全毁了！
It's ruined!
不，不是这样的! 我找到了! 在这里！
No, that's not true! I found it! Here it is!
- 我找到了! 这里! - 将军..
- I found it! Here! - General...
将军... 将军..
General... General....
- 什么? - 教皇在等你
- What? - His Holiness is waiting for you.
好，我来了
Yes, yes. I am coming.
就来
I'm coming.
东正教牧首辖区 斯雷姆斯基卡尔洛夫奇
ORTHODOX PATRIARCHATE, SREMSKI KARLOVCI,
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS, AND SLOVENES
我的孩子
My son,
你确定你要走吗？
are you sure you need to go?
教皇大人
Your Holiness,
我什么都不确定了
I am not sure of anything anymore.
最重要的是不要失去对上帝的信仰
The most important thing is not to lose faith in God.
我不会失去对上帝的信仰
I'm not losing my faith in our Lord,
但我对人们失去了信心
but I am losing my faith in people.
你不能宽恕吗？
You cannot forgive?
人是我们主的形象，不要忘记这一点
A man is an image of our Lord, do not forget that.
现在是那人向主显现的时候了
It is time for that man to present himself to the Lord
他可以因此得到公正的评价
So he can be judged fairly.
如果他是为了地狱，那就随他去吧
If he is for Hell, then let him go to Hell.
感谢上帝，我们不是做决定的人
Thank God, we are not the ones to decide.
您说得对，教皇大人，我们无法决定
You are right, Your Holiness. We cannot decide.
但是我们可以预测
But we can anticipate.
别担心，教皇大人，我会战斗到底的
Don't worry, Your Holiness, I will fight till the end.
我们祈祷吧
Let us pray.
兄弟们..
Brothers...
你知道我们为什么在这里
you know why we are here
是什么苦难迫使我们这么做
and what misery made us do this.
塞尔维亚人说: “马其顿是我们的!”
The Serbs say: "Macedonia is ours!"
保加利亚人说: “马其顿是我们的!”
The Bulgarians say: "Macedonia is ours!"
希腊人也说: “马其顿是我们的!”
The Greek say: "Macedonia is ours!"
但什么是我们的? ! 什么是马其顿的？
But what the fuck is ours?! What is Macedonian?
他们说即使是马其顿的国王亚历山大也不是马其顿人
They say that even Alexander the Macedonian wasn't a Macedonian.
那他到底是什么? 为什么他被称为马其顿人
What the fuck was he then? And why was he called Macedonian,
如果他不是马其顿人? 那就见鬼去吧！
if he wasn't Macedonian? To hell with him!
- 我听说... - 闭嘴，你个白痴！
- I've heard that... - Shut up, you idiot!
为马其顿而战是我们的职责
The fight for Macedonia is our duty,
和我们的命运
and our destiny.
如果那些希腊人，保加利亚人，塞尔维亚人
And if some Greek, Bulgarian, Serb
- 克罗地亚人? - 你他妈给我闭嘴！
- A Croat? - Shut the fuck up!
如果有人妨碍我，我就会..
And if someone stands in my way, he will get...
把他老二塞嘴里，然后给他一张单程票
my dick... And a one-way ticket,
- 那张票... - 通往地狱
- And that way leads to... - It leads to hell.
没错，安琪! 你终于开窍了
That's right, Angelche! Finally something clever from you.
准备好，我们要走了！
Get ready! We're leaving!
我想补充一点
I would like to add something:
你只能和我哥哥一起回布科沃
You can return to Bukovo only with my brother,
决不能丢下他，明白吗？
and by no means without him. Is that clear?
如果我哥哥命中注定，要把尸骨留在贝尔格莱德
If it's Damyan's destiny to leave his bones here in Belgrade,
那你也要留下
then you will leave yours too.
督察…
Inspector...
我听说杀你的凶手逃到另一个世界去了
I heard that your murderer escaped... to the other world.
这不是我的问题，博士
That's the least of my problems, dear doctor.
你有时间跟我聊聊吗？
Do you have some time for me?
他们是一群狂热分子，一个教派
They are dangerous men, fanatics, a sect.
对于北方人来说，这是太阳的象征
This is the symbol of Sun for the people from the north.
德国人称之为日耳曼民族
The Germans would call it Germanic,
但我觉得他们有点自命不凡
but I think they're a bit pretentious.
长矛上的铭文是什么意思？
The inscription on the lance?
上帝与我们同在
"Nobiskum Deus" God is with us.
这是朗基努斯本人
It's a motto of Roman legions
隶属的罗马军团座右铭
to which Longinus himself belonged.
随着长矛和它的复制品不断易主
As the lance and its copies changed their owners,
座右铭也从一支军队转移到另一支军队
the motto moved from one army to another.
从君士坦丁到查理曼大帝
From Constantine to Charlemagne,
从拿破仑到俄罗斯帝国军队
and from Napoleon to the Imperial Russian Army.
第一次世界大战时奥地利人也有“Gott mit Uns”（上帝与我们同在）
Austrians in the Great War had "Gott mit Uns"
你还记得？
You remembered?
- 是的 - 我也记得
- I did. - Me too.
还有银行的这个章程
And this sign on the bank,
有什么关联？
what does that have to do with it?
- 这是巧合吗? - 我不相信巧合
- Is it a coincidence? - I don't believe in coincidences.
达维多维奇来自维也纳的秘密伙伴是谁？
And who is Davidovich's secret partner from Vienna?
- 有人认识他吗? - 没有
- Does anybody know him? - No.
至少玛雅 · 达维多维奇说她不认识
At least Maya Davidovich says she doesn't know him.
应该调查一下，也许我应该去维也纳
That should be checked. Maybe I should go to Vienna.
请留意贝尔格莱德这里的情况
Please, keep an eye on the things, here in Belgrade.
好好保管长矛
And take good care of the lance.
它可能是真品
It may turn out to be the original.
- 下午好，先生 - 我们得谈谈
- Good afternoon, sir. - We need to talk.
谁? 你和我？
Who? You and I?
找别人吧，我不是告密者
Find someone else. I'm not a snitch.
- 这是私人事务 - 你想要女人？
- This is personal. - Ah, you want pussy?
城里有很多妓女，没必要来这里毁了你的漂亮鞋子
There are whores in the city. No need to ruin your fancy shoes.
- 玛拉在哪儿? - 谁? 那个妓女？
- Where is Mara? - Who? That hooker?
- 她怎么了? - 她失踪了
- What about her? - She disappeared.
穷人就是这样，亲爱的探长
It happens with the poor, dear Inspector.
人们来了又走，然后又回来
People come and go, and then they return.
他们挨家挨户求一碗汤喝
They go from door to door, looking for a bowl of soup,
为了赚两个硬币跟野男人做爱
They fuck for two coins.
但是像你这样一个时髦的家伙怎么会知道呢？
But how can a posh guy like you know that?
现在给我滚出去！
Now get the fuck out!
我不想见到你！
I don't want to see you!
- 把刀放下 - 别激动，年轻人
- Put the knife down. - Take it easy, son.
- 我说了，把刀放下! - 放松，会有人受伤的
- I said, put the knife down! - Easy. Someone may get hurt. Okay.
- 别激动，你怎么回事? - 玛拉在哪？
- Easy, what's wrong with you? - Where's Mara?
放松！
Easy!
玛拉在哪儿！
Where is Mara?!
你听到了吗! 在哪儿? ！
Do you hear me! Where?!
我操！
Oh, fuck!
拜托，斯维塔，换辆新车吧
C'mon, Sveta? Get rid of that junk.
这不是我能决定的
It's not up to me.
你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
突袭“撒马尔罕”
There's a raid on "Samarkand".
突袭俄罗斯俱乐部? 你确定？
Raid on a Russian club? Are you sure?
他们说很紧急
They said it's urgent.
局长知道吗？
Does Dimitriyevich know about it?
当然，就是他下的命令
Sure, he's the one who ordered it.
- 这是怎么回事，日沃因? - 我不知道
- What is this, Zhivoyin? - I don't know.
整天都有这样的事情发生，最近一次是在贝洛尼市场
There are incidents all day. The latest at Bayloni market.
看起来像是一场没有德国人的战争
Looks like a war without the Germans.
- 准备好了吗? - 好了
- Ready? - Yes.
小心点，别在法庭上胡说八道
Be careful. Don't go out speaking nonsense.
别担心我
Don't worry about me.
我怎么能不担心
How can I not worry, you're crazy.
这可能是我们最后一支烟，也是最后一次聊天
This may be our last cig. And our last chat.
他们又不会马上杀了你
Well, it's not like they're gonna shoot you right away.
你知道这个国家的官僚主义，还有时间…
You know the bureaucracy in this country. It'll take time...
谢谢你所做的一切，塔尼
Thanks for everything, Tane.
再见
And goodbye.
走吧，伙计们！
Come on, boys!
警察! 不许动！
Police! Nobody moves!
上尉，这是搜查令！
Captain, the warrant!
督察先生，请坐，喝一杯
Inspector. Sit down, grab a drink.
我们来这不是为了鸦片和妓女
We're not here for opium and hookers,
是想激怒一些人
but to ruffle some feathers.
你在哪里看到鸦片或妓女？
Where do you see opium or whores?
我们会找到的，来吧，快点！
We'll find them. C'mon, hurry up!
- 有发现什么吗? - 没有
- Anything? - Nothing.
什么意思，什么都没有？
How do you mean, nothing?
本俱乐部暂停营业，等候进一步通知
This club is closed until further notice.
- 让这老头住手 - 别弹了！
- And tell this geezer to stop it. - Stop playing!
如栅！
Ruzha!
这是怎么回事，大家都去哪儿了？
What the hell is this. Where is everybody?
到处都是一片混乱，好像战争爆发了一样
It's a chaos all over the place, as if the war broke out.
你不仅没有能力组织公正的审判…
Not only you're incapable to organise a fair trial...
就算是逮捕嫌疑犯对你来说也是个问题
Even arresting a suspect is a problem for you.
王国里有些东西腐烂了…
Well, something's rotten in the Kingdom...
这是怎么回事？
What is it?
格拉夫贾查监狱发生了武装袭击
There's been an armed attack on Glavnjacha prison.
这就是腐烂的象征
Symbolic, indeed.
我们走
Let's go.